<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Players Visible]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>site-lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>Players Visible</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 21:26:43 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="site-lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 21:26:32 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[Session 0 Introduction]]></title><description><![CDATA[Welcome to the continent of Amuth, a land of rugged frontiers, imperial expansion, and ancient, shifting powers. As common citizens of the Empire or travellers seeking fortune, the following is what you would know as you walk the streets of a major hub like Stormrest or prepare for the long road west.The Empire of Brateranth is the dominant political force in the known world, though its grip loosens the further you travel from the coast.
The Sanction on Magic: All arcane magic—spells cast by Magic-Users—is strictly illegal unless registered and sanctioned by the Imperial Administration. Magi of the Empire: These robed enforcers, serve as the Empire's "arcane police" hunting down "wild" or unregistered casters. Taxation and Order: Imperial soldiers, led by officers, are a constant presence, focused on collecting trade tariffs and maintaining a rigid, often brutal, version of "order". Unlike arcane magic, the power of the Elemental Gods is a respected and legal part of daily life.
Clerical Administration: Clerics are the sanctioned spiritual leaders of the Empire. They are responsible for maintaining the elemental ley lines—invisible conduits of divine energy that keep the world in balance. Divine vs. Arcane: To a general citizen, the distinction is clear: Clerics are keepers of the natural order, while "wild" mages are dangerous threats to it. Most travellers find themselves in the port city of Stormrest, the gateway to the "New World".
The Gold Rush: Rumors are flying about a massive gold strike in the northern mining camp of Fraf. It is a place of "mud and raw lumber," attracting anyone looking to get rich—and the complications that come with them. Wilderness Dangers: Beyond the boundary stones of the core provinces, the "Peace of the Empire" thins. The roads are plagued by bandits, oversized vermin, and the occasional elven hunting party. The Elven Nations: The land to the west of Stormrest technically belongs to the Elven Nations. While the Empire claims the territory and collects taxes, the local Elves often view travelers as trespassers on their ancestral lands.
]]></description><link>jounals/session-0-introduction.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Jounals/Session 0 Introduction.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 21:05:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Elven Nations]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Elven Nations are a collection of Tribes of the Elvish Race. They are a set of tribes with complex inter-tribal politics with alliances and enemies between tribes. The elven people have a Tribal system with inter-tribal war common.Elves are treated with distrust and are not welcomed into the colonial towns. They can travel into the towns, but are not welcome in public taverns and saloons. Different Tribes have different relationships with the colonists, some tribes are 'friendly' and are accepted and even hired for tracking and for labour on farmsteads. Other tribes are known as 'hostile' and are feared and at time hunted as dangerous threats to 'civilisation'.]]></description><link>5-organisations/elven-nations.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5- Organisations/Elven Nations.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 21:03:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dwarves]]></title><description><![CDATA[The dwarves are migrants from the 'Old world' in the East and are migrating for many reasons. One reason is to find the wealth in the ground of <a data-href="Amuth" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Amuth</a>, another is for religious freedom. A schism has occurred in Dwarven society based on the rise of the 'New' dwarven gods, these reformist gods are in direct conflict with the 'old' gods. The migrants tend to be of the 'New' god variety.]]></description><link>5-organisations/dwarves.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5- Organisations/Dwarves.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 21:02:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pasted image 20251228074828]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="pasted-image-20251228074828.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>pasted-image-20251228074828.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Pasted image 20251228074828.png</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 20:48:28 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Stormrest]]></title><description><![CDATA[Stormrest is no longer a simple provincial town, but the major coastal hub for the Old World Empire's trade and military projection into this territory. Its prosperity is visible in the massive stone docks and fortified walls, but this wealth is entirely built on imperial extraction. The city is divided into three distinct zones: the Imperial Citadel, the bustling Port District, and the impoverished, resentful Old Town.The atmosphere is heavy with resentment. Imperial soldiers patrol rigidly, and citizens often gather in tight groups, whispering about the harsh Trade Tariffs and the Governor's Autocratic Rule. Revolution is not yet open, but the embers are glowing. Location: Built atop the highest bluff, overlooking the entire city and harbor. It is highly fortified.
The Governor's Palace: The seat of power, home to <a data-href="Governor Valerius" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Governor Valerius</a>(The Iron Fist). He is paranoid, rarely leaves the Citadel, and relies on <a data-href="Imperial Army" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Imperial Army</a> to maintain order. He is the ultimate source of the high taxes and is fiercely anti-representation.
The Tax Office: All official paperwork, licenses, and trade taxes are processed here. A PC needs a "Citizen Pass" (5gp, valid for 30 days) just to conduct business outside of the Port District. <br>The Merchant Guildhall: Where <a data-href="Merrick Bramblecart" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Merrick Bramblecart</a> (and likely his contacts) does business. The Guild is currently split: wealthy merchants support the Empire for protection, while smaller traders (like Merrick) resent the exorbitant tariffs.
The City Gate (Now the Imperial Checkpoint): Heavily guarded (4 well-equipped Imperial Soldiers at all times). The Trade Tax: Any goods leaving Stormrest toward Fraf are subject to a 25% tariff levied by the Empire.
Contraband: Imperial law is strict. Possession of unlicenced magic items or powerful weapons is grounds for seizure and detainment (DC 14 Save or 1d6 days in Imperial Jail). <br>The "Unburdened Hand" Tavern: A notoriously dingy tavern in the slums that serves as the unofficial meeting spot for the burgeoning <a data-href="The Restless Hearth" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Restless Hearth</a> Faction (the revolutionaries). Propaganda: Pamphlets and posters discussing "Taxation Without Representation" are often slipped into pockets or left on tables here. ]]></description><link>3-locations/stormrest.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">3- Locations/Stormrest.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 20:40:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Factions]]></title><link>5-organisations/factions.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5- Organisations/Factions.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 21:01:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[index]]></title><description><![CDATA[Table9 resultsSort2Filter0PropertiesNewfile nameObjTypeObjTypeJournal<a class="internal-link" href="jounals/session-0-introduction.html" draggable="true" target="_self">Session 0 Introduction</a>JournalJournalObjTypeLocation<a class="internal-link" href="3-locations/farsee.html" draggable="true" target="_self">Farsee</a>LocationLocation<a class="internal-link" href="3-locations/fraf.html" draggable="true" target="_self">Fraf</a>LocationLocation<a class="internal-link" href="3-locations/stormrest.html" draggable="true" target="_self">Stormrest</a>LocationLocationObjTypeNone<a class="internal-link" href="index.html" draggable="true" target="_self">index.base</a><a class="internal-link" href="5-organisations/factions.html" draggable="true" target="_self">Factions</a><a class="internal-link" href="pasted-image-20251228074828.html" draggable="true" target="_self">Pasted image 20251228074828.png</a><a class="internal-link" href="5-organisations/dwarves.html" draggable="true" target="_self">Dwarves</a><a class="internal-link" href="5-organisations/elven-nations.html" draggable="true" target="_self">Elven Nations</a>]]></description><link>index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">index.base</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 10:23:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fraf]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a data-href="Fraf" href="3-locations/fraf.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Fraf</a> is a small mining camp 200 miles inland of <a data-href="Stormrest" href="3-locations/stormrest.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Stormrest</a> on the continent of <a data-href="Amuth" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Amuth</a>, the Northern Continent of the New World. It is not in the colonies <a data-href="Empire of Brateranth" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Empire of Brateranth</a>, rather it is in the <a data-href="Elven Nations" href="5-organisations/elven-nations.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Elven Nations</a>.<br>It has no <a data-href="Imperial Administration" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Imperial Administration</a> control and no rule-of law.
There are some large mines but mostly there are people panning the rivers and streams in the surrounds. All manner of people from all manner of places are in town.The towns leadership is the mostly corrupt owners of various businesses who have the money to buy muscle.<br>Having said this, the <a data-href="Empire of Brateranth" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Empire of Brateranth</a> absolutely claims the town and it collects taxes. Although they provide only basic security with a largely corrupt and incompetent Imperial Guard. <br><a data-href="Dwarves" href="5-organisations/dwarves.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Dwarves</a> have a mining venture and are allied with the <a data-href="Gnomes" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Gnomes</a> who have built a water powered Gold crushing and extraction mill.The reach of the empire is too wide and their resources too thin to control another whole continent away from their homeland although they are building a tower in the town and have posted Guardsmen, they struggle to maintin strong momentum.Key among the challenges is contending with the Elvish Tribe and there resistant to the taking of their land.]]></description><link>3-locations/fraf.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">3- Locations/Fraf.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 06:23:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Farsee]]></title><link>3-locations/farsee.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">3- Locations/Farsee.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 06:23:28 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>